[Music]
have you ever wanted to package data in
your business Central extension it could
be any data it could be test data it
could be sample data to pre-populate
some records with it could be
configuration files um well if you've
ever wanted to do something like that I
have something cooking for you or
actually it's cooked if you are using
business Central 25.2 or later
um and to illustrate how this works uh
let me show you I have this new
extension
here and it is in the spirit of cooking
a list of
recipes and you can specify a name of a
dish which Cuisine it belongs to and
optionally an image uh that uh
represents the dish and here I have an
action to load some data ha now I have a
whole bunch of dishes
um pre-populated and also some of them
even have blob data associated with it
how did I do this did I hide these
images as base 64 strings in a text uh
variable um did I hardcode all of these
I did not and I'm going to show you how
this works with resources now let's
switch over to visual studio code where
all the fun
happens so I have uh in my Al files I'll
go to the AL first uh in my Al files
I've got well the first few objects
aren't very interesting I've just got
like a table to store the um fields that
I want I have a page to display what I
want to display but the most interesting
thing here is the load action how did I
load all those records now I'm not going
to go through all the ours uh but what I
want to call out here the first thing
here is this function nav app.get
Resource as Json um and this is how we
interact with resources there's a bunch
of convenience functions like this so if
I go and na
app.get resource so we have get resource
get Resource as Json get Resource as
text they're used for different things
um get Resource as Json get Resource as
text they should be
self-explanatory um gets a resource as a
Json object and get Resource as a text
and then you have get resource for
arbitrary things
um if I uh look at this I I see that I'm
reading a resource called recipe index
Json and those of you with an astute eye
can see that I actually have this file
here under the resources folder um I
also have a bunch of images for some of
them and how do I say hey this folder
should be the folder which I select my
resources uh it's very simple in the
app. Json there is a new property called
resource folders and you just specify
whichever folder you want uh you may
notice that this is an array uh this
means you can specify multiple resource
folders if you want up to you um I've
just got my my single folder with a
subfolder
underneath uh and so the first thing I
do is I read the Json object from using
get resources at Json then I'm not going
to go over the how the J how I interact
with the Json but I just iterate over it
get a whole bunch of values out of it
and then I also want to know hey do I
have an image associated with this dish
and the way I do that is with another
function that you can use to intera with
resources and that is nav app. list
resources um as you can see here I've
got images uh Ward J uh basically it
means um give me all the resources that
match uh this pattern um if you don't do
a w cut you can also do something like
this you can also do uh just get me
everything in the images folder that
also works or you can say get me
everything if you pass nothing inside
you will get abs every single resource
available to your
app and here I'm just reading the
resource as into an instream and then
later on I'm just copying that instream
into the records blob um and that was it
it is that simple um if I want to add
more images I can just throw more images
into the folder uh if I want to add more
records just add more lines to my Json
file here and it works now there are
some important limitations with
resources that you should be aware of
the first and most important limitation
is that resources can only be accessed
within the app that owns them this means
if I have another app that depends on
this app I cannot access these resources
directly I cannot use nav app get
resource recipe index or Json to get the
recipe index from this app so need per
app um the other thing is that we treat
resources as code what does this mean uh
whenever you run into uh resource
exposure policies so um if you specify
allow downloading Source resources will
be downloaded with the source code um if
you set this to false it will not be
included in the source
code um and on top of that there are
some limitations I don't remember of
them off the top of my head but luckily
I have also documented them so there's
this very nice page here adding an
access resources in business Central
extensions and here you can see exactly
what I just mentioned how to what the um
how to specify it the functions you have
to use um but here the limits so any
single resource file can be up to 16
megabytes the total size of all resource
files has to be under 256 for a single
extension and you can have up to 256
files in an extension we may change this
as we collect uh data on usage just to
optimize our system but this is what the
limits are for now um yeah and that is
everything for my demonstration of
resources and I hope to see you using
resources in your extensions as well
thank you very much for joining me